solodsergev287@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergeisolod https://sergeisolod.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Middle Frontend developer (4 years 5 months years full time) with deep understanding of developing complex Single Page Applications in product companies (about 20 commercial products used by thousands of people), expert level of JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS and other technologies. I have extensive expertise in supporting projects that are developed by other frontend developers, including legacy code support. I have deep qualification in front-end projects development from idea to production in startups, as well as great experience in teamwork on large projects.

# **Experience**

Digift

Middle Frontend Developer

Remote (Thessaloniki, Greece) Feb 2020 - Present (3 years 5 months)

- I've developed about 20 complex SPAs (admin panels, online stores, widgets and others) from idea to production. I have done this in a large team of developers, testers, analysts, designers (Agile, Scrum). These projects are used by tens of thousands of people, they bring my company hundreds of thousands dollars.
- I supported all projects in this company, including legacy code, I fixed bugs, implemented features, improved existing projects. This allowed my company to increase sales and improve its reputation.
- I was fully responsible for most of the projects of my company (the front-end part), my area of responsibility was the performance of these projects in production.
- I participated in the architectural development of the projects. Many fundamental decisions were made by me, such as the choice of technologies, programming language, architecture, and so on. This allowed my company to use the latest technology and best practice.
- I trained and mentored the employees of this company, and also made training videos for colleagues, clients and developers. Thanks to this, new employees quickly began to bring profit to the company.
- I've done SEO optimization of our projects on React (Next, Node), developed email letters, WebSocket payment processor, SPA with authorization and token, complex animations with json, images. This allowed my company to appear more often in Google search results and present a quality product to users.

Foodle

On-site (St Petersburg City, Russia) Feb 2019 - Jan 2020 (1 year)

### Junior Frontend Developer

- I've developed a SPA (React, Redux) that helps to see restaurant menus and order food in advance. This is the main business model of my company, the SPA that I developed allowed the company to increase revenue and occupy the market.
- Together with the team leader, backend developers and testers I participated in the development of the future project architecture. I suggested ideas that were implemented and reduced the load on the server, increased the productivity of the project.
- I fixed the bugs of the company's main website, implemented a lot of features and it improved my company's reputation.

Freelance

Remote (St Petersburg City, Russia) May 2018 - Jan 2019 (9 months)

### **Frontend Developer**

- Using HTML5, CSS3, Saas, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Gulp, Figma, Zeplin I developed many websites for my clients, which allowed them to be represented on the Internet, sell services, increase revenue and sales, improve reputation.
- I supported my clients' sites, fixed errors and bugs, introduced new features, I also supported the CMS platforms WordPress, Wix, Joomla. This increased the sales funnel, because now customers did not face problems and site bugs.
- I implemented in the site code all the tools necessary for comfortable work, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager and libraries. This allowed my clients to see statistics, work comfortably, find their weaknesses and increase sales.

## Skills

**Technical:** JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS3, Saas, HTML5, NextJS, VueJS, Webpack, Babel.js, Gulp, REST APIs, WebSocket, Jest, ESLint, jQuery, MaterialUI, Bootstrap, Git, Terminal macOS/Linux.

Other: Jira, Figma, Zeplin, Scrum, Agile, UI, UX, Wordpress, Wix, Joomla, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager.

# **Educational**

### Saint Petersburg State University